[narrator] In the Dentora region
of the Republic of Padokea,
there is a dormant volcano
surrounded by forests
measuring 3722 meters high
called Kukuroo Mountain.
It is home to a family
of famous assassins:
The Zoldyck family.
Visitors arrive every day in hopes
of catching a glimpse of the mansion,
which has never been seen.
It’s one of this nation’s
most popular tourist attractions.
LAMENTATION TOURS
[theme song playing]
Very well.
You’re free to go now.
But, Kil…
Promise me one thing…
That you will never betray your friends.
Got that?
I’ll never betray them.
I swear.
CAN'T SEE x IF x YOU'RE BLIND
[narrator] After speaking with his father,
whom he greatly admires,
Killua leaves home once again,
despite his mother’s objections.
Canary leads Gon and his friends
to the butler’s quarters,
in an attempt to meet with Killua.
[tired exhale] Are we there yet?
Still a bit farther.
[Leorio sighs]
But we’ve been walking forever…
[Kikyo] Oh, I am positively furious!
Kil finally came home to us
but my husband’s
allowed him to leave again!
And Father is just as guilty,
releasing him
without asking my permission!
Honestly! Every single time!
They all just act
without consulting me first!
Understand, Gotoh?
[Gotoh] Yes, ma'am.
[Kikyo sobs]
This... This is
a most critical time for Kil.
Why doesn’t anyone understand?
[sobs lightly]
He’s the one child I shall not give up!
[Kikyo sobbing]
[frogs croaking]
[Canary] There it is.
[Leorio] That’s it, huh?
It’s still a lot farther away
than I’d like.
Hey, Canary.
Aren’t you gonna get
in a lot of trouble with your bosses
for bringing us here?
They are perfectly aware
of what I’m doing.
I am quite certain of that.
I’m prepared for the consequences.
If there’s any trouble,
I’ll take responsibility.
No. I am merely serving as a guide
for Master Killua’s friends.
Master Killua.
We’ve been waiting for you.
Gotoh.
Where is Gon right now?
You know, don’t you?
Canary is bringing Master Gon
along with his two friends,
even as we speak.
Seriously?
They’ll be arriving shortly,
so please wait inside.
Sure.
-Gotoh.
-Sir.
The second he’s here, tell me.
[Gotoh]
Of course. I shall notify you immediately.
Please forgive me Master Killua.
[Leorio] We finally made it!
Welcome, gentlemen.
[Gotoh]
We apologize for our previous discourtesy.
We have been informed
by the lady of the house
that from now on
you are to be treated as official guests.
There, does that feel better?
It does! Thank you!
Then this isn’t the main residence?
No. This is the butler’s quarters.
Now please make yourselves comfortable.
Look, thanks for the hospitality
but we only came here to see Killua.
So, can you take us to him?
Like, now?
That won’t be necessary, sir.
Master Killua is on his way
this very moment.
-Wait, really?
-[cups clatter]
[Gotoh]
That’s right. So please be patient.
-Great news, huh, Gon?
-Yep!
[Gotoh] Now then…
It would be so tedious
to just sit and wait.
[smirks]
I propose we pass the time with a game.
Game, you say?
Which hand holds the coin?
[all three] The left hand.
That is correct.
Now I’ll move more quickly this time.
Now. Which hand?
It’s the left again.
How marvelous.
Well. I shall have to try harder
this time.
So? Which hand?
I’m not sure, but...
I’d say right.
[Gotoh] You see…
I’ve known Master Killua his entire life
and I care for him as I would my own son.
In all honesty,
I despise you for attempting
to take him away.
Well, which hand?
Answer.
The left hand.
The lady’s voice was a bare whisper.
Her son is leaving
and it’s breaking her heart.
I can’t forgive you.
Before Master Killua arrives…
I shall test each of you
by my own methods.
You have no choice.
Canary!
[Gotoh] This is her punishment
for defying orders and bringing you here.
Allow me to explain the rules.
If you answer incorrectly you are out.
Should you all be disqualified
which is quite possible
then I shall tell Master Killua
that you left.
And that he will never see
any of you again.
-Killua is--
-[Gotoh] Silence!
Your very lives hang
by a most delicate thread.
Answer my question.
I will not ask again.
Now, which hand?
I couldn’t see it.
And time is of the essence.
You only have three seconds.
You!
Once three seconds have passed,
slit her throat.
Yes, sir.
Hold on! I pick the left hand!
-I pick the right hand!
-Yes, me too!
[Leorio gasps]
[frustrated grunt]
One has been disqualified.
This is useless. I can’t see anything!
Which hand?
I choose the right hand.
And I pick the left.
It was in my left hand.
Now only one remains.
-Here we go.
-Wait just a minute!
What is it?
If you’re trying to buy time,
I will kill one of you.
-Leorio! Gimme your knife.
-Huh?
Don’t worry, okay?
I’m not gonna use it for anything stupid.
He cut himself to reduce the swelling…
Dammit! How long do I have to wait?
Hey, Gotoh!
Is anybody out here?
What is going on?
There. Much better. I can see now.
Okay, I’m ready!
[derisive snort]
Which hand?
The left.
Very good. Now…
Now, which one of us has it?
HUNTER GLOSSARY
WAITING PERIOD
That guy. Right behind me.
[snorts]
-[butlers applaud]
-[Gotoh] Splendid. Well done!
Gotoh! Is Gon here yet?
-Killua!
-You were already here? Gon!
And this guy… um… Kurapika?
You remembered.
-Reolio!
-[yells] It’s Leorio!
It’s been so long! But you made it!
Wow! Your face is a mess!
Back at you!
[Gon and Killua laughing]
Hey, Gotoh! What happened to telling me
as soon as they got here, huh?
What were you doing?
Please forgive me.
I had them participate in a little game.
A game?
A joke, sir.
Though quite a poor one, admittedly.
I’m sorry for the trouble.
I do hope you enjoyed yourselves.
If that was a joke,
then you sure fooled me.
Wait, did they try anything?
No. They were just
keeping us all entertained.
Really? Well, okay.
Let’s go someplace else.
Like anywhere at all.
If we stay here,
my mom will chew all of us out.
Hm.
Hey, Gotoh. Listen.
No matter what Mom said, don’t follow me.
Understood, sir.
Please take care.
C’mon, Gon. Let’s go.
Bye.
Mister Gotoh...
You’re gonna miss Killua
when he’s gone, aren’t you?
No, sir.
It is our duty to serve our employers
and not to become
emotionally attached to them.
You liar.
[Gotoh] Gon.
Well? Which hand?
Your left one, right?
No way!
[Gotoh] Indeed. A deception.
The world is teeming
with tricks and tricksters.
Please be careful.
And please, sir, look after Master Killua.
See ya later, Canary!
[Killua] Hurry up, Gon!
[Gon] Coming, sorry!
[Killua] Let’s get out of here
before trouble finds us!
[Killua] Yeah.
He pulled that same trick on me.
Once you know the secret,
you’ll kick yourself for not seeing it.
Oh. Really?
I bet this is what he did.
-Which hand?
-Your left, right?
What the--?!
But how’d ya do it?
Gotoh must have had two coins
the entire time.
But it looked like he only had one.
Well he concealed a coin in his right hand
and then he flipped the other.
He let us see him grab the coin
using his left hand.
Now, this is where the skill comes in:
Before he asked us to choose
which hand held the coin,
he raised both of his arms like so…
and slipped the first coin
into his sleeve,
while keeping his hand
balled up in a fist.
Oh!
Then he just showed us the coin
in his right hand.
Yep, you got it.
[growls] That cheater!
Well, not the whole time, probably.
I’m sure just on the last turn.
Gotoh hates cheating,
even if it’s just a game.
Feel better?
[growls] That's even worse!
[train whistles]
What?
Wait. You came here on a tourist visa?
Mm-hm.
But you passed the Hunter Exam,
didn’t you?
So why didn’t you use your license?
You can use it to get into other countries
and stay for as long as you want!
We already told him that!
Not yet. No license.
Not until I finish what I have to do.
So, what is it? What do you gotta do?
Well… you remember…
When Hisoka game me his number badge!!
I will take it back
but only when you can
punch me in the face like that.
In the meantime,
you just hold on to it for me.
I’ll return it
whenever I can punch Hisoka
right in his stupid, ugly face!
Until I can do that, I’m not gonna
use my Hunter’s License
or go back to Whale Island!
Hmm... So? Where is Hisoka?
Uh?
Uh, well…
That’s what I thought…
I know where he is, Gon.
Really?
But how?
I know because he told me.
That’s what he said…
[Kurapika gasps]
[Hisoka whispers inaudibly]
No. After the orientation.
[Leorio] Yeah, but it’s related, right?
Perhaps.
Okay, look, I’ve been dying to ask.
Hisoka…
What did he say to you?
All he said was…
I’ll tell you something interesting
about spiders.
Did he mean the Phantom Troupe?
I don’t recall
ever mentioning them to Hisoka.
He either overheard our conversation
during the First Phase
or heard it from someone else.
The troupe’s symbol is the spider
which is what they are called
by anyone familiar with them.
I was interested in
whatever information he had.
I get it now.
Okay. That actually makes sense.
So that’s what made you swallow your pride
and take the win.
I asked him about it
after the orientation.
Meet me in Yorknew City
on September first.
But why that date?
That’s half a year away.
You’ve got plenty of time.
So, what’s gonna happen in Yorknew City?
Ha!
They’re holding
the world’s largest auction!
That’s right.
From September 1st
through September 10th,
there will be an auction,
with rare and unusual items
and national treasures
from around the world.
Of course, the event attracts
all manner of tricksters
who come looking to satisfy their greed.
It’s the biggest gathering of wealth
on the entire planet.
Oh…
Do you think that means
the troupe’s gonna be there?
Well, they are a group of bandits.
It’s unlikely that they
would let this opportunity slip by.
Regardless...
on that day,
Hisoka will be somewhere in Yorknew City.
Okay, then. September the first.
I got it. Thanks a lot!
[Kurapika] All right. I’ll be leaving now.
[Gon] Huh?
We all got to see Killua again,
so my work here is finished.
I’ll be needing a lot of money
if I’m going to attend the auction.
So, from here I shall search for a patron
willing to employ me as a Hunter.
Really?
I guess I should head back home, then.
Wait, you too?
I haven’t given up on becoming a doctor.
If I’m accepted to med school,
then this will pay
for the outrageous expenses.
I need to get back
and start hitting the books.
Best of luck, Leorio!
-[Leorio] ‘Til next time…
-[Kurapika] Yes. That will be…
[all] September first in Yorknew City!
See ya later!
[Gon] Bye-bye!
Guess it’s just you and me now, Killua.
So? What next?
You seriously have to ask me that?
We’ve gotta start training.
Oh. For what?
Why not have fun?
[Killua grunts]
You remember what you told me
about a second ago?
You think you can punch Hisoka in the face
without training?
[yells] That’d take ten years!
Forget about six months!
[Gon] Okay.
[Killua] Here. I’ll break it down for you.
This is Hisoka and this is Hanzo.
[Gon] Right, I’m with you,
[Killua] If this is the strength gap
between Hisoka and Hanzo...
the gap between you and Hisoka is...
[Killua] This wide!
And I’m being generous!
[Gon] That’s just mean!
Okay, then how far apart are you?
[Killua] Who, me?
Well, probably here…
Wow! I’m so humble!
Oh...
So Hanzo’s the stronger one?
Wait…
What is it?
[Gon] You really are awesome, Killua!
Knock it off, all right?
It’s embarrassing.
It’s just I don’t know
how to tell the difference in strength
between my opponent and me.
[Killua] It doesn’t really matter, dummy.
I’m only estimating, anyway.
Besides, you get the general idea, right?
And with experience, your estimates
will become more accurate.
But the stronger someone is,
the better they can hide that strength.
So, it’s not a method that I’d recommend.
Okay, I won’t.
[Killua] Point is...
Hisoka’s really strong.
[Gon] Yeah.
With just six months,
we’re gonna need to get real creative.
[grunts]
[Killua] Hey… got any money?
[sheepish exhale]
I’m a little low, actually.
I don’t have much either.
But there’s a place
where we can make ourselves some money
and train at the same time.
Make money while we’re training?
At the Heavens Arena.
Heavens Arena?
Yeah! I’ll explain later.
But we really ought to get going now!
[Gon] Right!
[narrator] After bidding farewell
to Kurapika and Leorio,
as well as promising to meet again
in Yorknew City,
Gon and Killua move on to a new stage:
the Heavens Arena.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Next time: “Then x And x After”!
Sweet and spicy!
[Mito] Salty and spicy!
[Gon] Spicy is good for you!